British Labour History Ephemera on Microfilm 5573 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Items 201-213, 1888-1897; Microfilm (Reel 20)
  - Item 9: Mass Meeting, Publication (Reel 20)
    By Leicester Anarchist-Communists. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Public Lecture, Publication (Reel 20)
    By Leicester Chirstian Socialist Society. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Labor Day Demostration, Publication (Reel 20)
    By Leicester Trades Council. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: May Day Demonstration, Publication (Reel 20)
  - Item 13: London Dock Laborers' Strike - Mass Meeting, Publication (Reel 20)
- Items 214-235, 1888-1897; Microfilm (Reel 21)
  - Item 1: London Dock Laborer's Strike - Mass Meeting, Publication (Reel 21)
  - Item 2: London Revolutionists - The Engineers Lock Out, Publication (Reel 21)
  - Item 3: Lord Overturn: Chrome, Charity, Crystals, an Cant, Publication (Reel 21)
    White Slaves' Series No. 3. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: The Case for an Eight Hours Day, Publication (Reel 21)
    By MacDonald, J.A. Murray. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Machine Room Charts, Publication (Reel 21)
    By Maguire, Tom. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: A Remembrance, Publication (Reel 21)
  - Item 7: A Labor Programme, Publication (Reel 21)
    By Mahon, J.L. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Manifesto of the Bradford Unemployed Emergency Committee, Publication (Reel 21)
  - Item 9: The Development of the Labor Movement, Publication (Reel 21)
    By Mann, Tom. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: The Eight Hours Movement, Publication (Reel 21)
  - Item 11: The International Labor Movement, Publication (Reel 21)
  - Item 12: The Programme of the ILP and the Unemployed, Publication (Reel 21)
  - Item 13: The "New" Trades Unionism, Publication (Reel 21)
    By Mann, Tom and Ben Tillett. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Wage-Labor & Capital, Publication (Reel 21)
    By Marx, Karl. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Manifesto of the Communist Party, Publication (Reel 21)
    By Marx, Karl and Frederick Engels. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: The Working-Class Movement in England, Publication (Reel 21)
    By Marx-Aveling, Eleanor. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Mr. H.H. Champion on the Australian Strike, Publication (Reel 21)
    By Maxwell, Herbet. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: An Address, Publication (Reel 21)
    By Manton, Reuben. Item is in English.
  - Item 19: A Meeting, Publication (Reel 21)
  - Item 20: "Merrie England" Fayre, Publication (Reel 21)
  - Item 21: Mineral Rents and Royalties, Tract No. XLIII, Publication (Reel 21)
  - Item 22: Minority Reports of the Royal Commission on Labor, Publication (Reel 21)
- Item 236, 1885; Microfilm (Reel 22)
  - Item 1: Monthly Report Amalgamated Society of Engineers, Publication (Reel 22)
- Items 237-250, 1882-1899; Microfilm (Reel 23)
  - Item 1: More About Overtoun (White Slaves Series - No. 4), Publication (Reel 23)
  - Item 2: Reply to a Liberal Non-Conformist Elector, Publication (Reel 23)
    By Morley, Saml. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Alfred Linnell - Memorial with a Death Song, Publication (Reel 23)
    By Morris, William. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Ancoats Brotherhood - When Adam Delved and Eve Span, Publication (Reel 23)
  - Item 5: How I Became a Socialist, Publication (Reel 23)
  - Item 6: Little Journeys to the Homes of English Authors, No. 1 by Elbert Hubbard, Publication (Reel 23)
  - Item 7: Monopoly, or How Labor is Robbed, Publication (Reel 23)
  - Item 8: True and False Society, Publication (Reel 23)
  - Item 9: Useful Work versus Useless Toil, Publication (Reel 23)
  - Item 10: The Why I Arms, Publication (Reel 23)
    By Morris, William and E.D. Bevington. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Man's Massage to Man, Publication (Reel 23)
    By Morse, J.J. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Poverty and Drunkenness (A Socialist's View), Publication (Reel 23)
    By Muse, Charles E. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Child Labor and the Half-Time System, Publication (Reel 23)
    By McMillan, Margaret. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Journal of the National Agricultural Union, Publication (Reel 23)
    By N.A.U. Cablwe. Item is in English.
- Items 251-252, 1884-1898; Microfilm (Reel 24)
  - Item 1: National Union of Woolsorters Public Meeting, Publication (Reel 24)
  - Item 2: A New Age (Oct. 1894-Dec. 1895), Publication (Reel 24)
- Items 253-269, 1879-1899; Microfilm (Reel 25)
  - Item 1: A New Catechism of Socialism, Publication (Reel 25)
  - Item 2: White upon Black: Short Narratives by a Dweller in the Region of White Chalk of his Descebt into the Region of Black Coal, Publication (Reel 25)
    By Newman, George. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Operative Bricklayers Society - Contribution Card, Publication (Reel 25)
  - Item 4: Operative Bricklayers Society - Key to Emblem, Publication (Reel 25)
  - Item 5: Oswald's Political Diary, Publication (Reel 25)
  - Item 6: Horror, Publication (Reel 25)
    By Overtoun. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Pauper Children - the Boarding out and Other Systems, Publication (Reel 25)
  - Item 8: The Social Revolution: How to Bring it About in a Peaceful Manner, A Definite Proposal, Publication (Reel 25)
    By Penisoplute, Phil. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Nine Rents and Mineral Royalties, Publication (Reel 25)
    By Percy, C.M. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: The Railways for the Nation, Publication (Reel 25)
    By Perris, G.H. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Our Foreign Commerce and Free Trade Policy, Publication (Reel 25)
    By Pim, J.T. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Anarchism and Socialism, Publication (Reel 25)
    By Pleschanoff, George. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Explosions in Collieries and their Cure, Publication (Reel 25)
    By Plimsoll, Samual. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: 12 Millions per Annum Wasted in the Sea, Publication (Reel 25)
  - Item 15: The Workman's View of Fair Trade, Publication (Reel 25)
    By Potter, George. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: The Marriage of Labor and Capital, Publication (Reel 25)
    By Pratt, Hodgson. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Progress, Publication (Reel 25)
    By G.W. Foote and Edward Aveling. January 1883- December 1887. Item is in English.
- Item 269, 1884-1885; Microfilm (Reel 26)
  - Item 1: Progress (continued), Publication (Reel 26)
    By G.W. Foote and Edward Aveling. Item is in English.
- Item 269, 1886-1887; Microfilm (Reel 27)
  - Item 1: Progress (continued), Publication (Reel 27)
- Items 270-276, 1880-1902; Microfilm (Reel 28)
  - Item 1: The Three Estates or Household Suffrage in its Relation to Labor and Capital, Publication (Reel 28)
    By Publicola. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Bimetallic Bubble, Publication (Reel 28)
    By Quelch, H. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Economics of Labor, Publication (Reel 28)
  - Item 4: Eight Hours for Work, Publication (Reel 28)
    By Rae, John. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Report of the Land Nationalization Society, Publication (Reel 28)
    1885-86 and 1898-99. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Report of the Labor Movement in the USA to the International Socialist and Trade Union Congress, Publication (Reel 28)
    July 27, 1896. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: The New Party, described by some of its members, Publication (Reel 28)
    By Reid, Andrew. Item is in English.
- Items 277-281, 1893-1900; Microfilm (Reel 29)
  - Item 1: Vox Clamantium: the Gospel of the People, Publication (Reel 29)
  - Item 2: How it can be done, 2nd Edition, Publication (Reel 29)
    By Richardson, John. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: The Eight-Hour Question, Publication (Reel 29)
    By Robertson, J.M. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Over-Population: A lecture, Publication (Reel 29)
  - Item 5: Rochdale Labor News, Publication (Reel 29)
    Jan. 1899 - April 1900. Item is in English.
- Items 282-288, 1882-1898; Microfilm (Reel 30)
  - Item 1: Rochdale School Board Election, Publication (Reel 30)
    Nov. 1891. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Practical Socialism, Publication (Reel 30)
    By Rogers, William. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: How our Working People Live, Publication (Reel 30)
    By Rowe, Richard. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Rules of the Amaglamated Society of Engineers, Publication (Reel 30)
    1885, 1892. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Rules of the Iron and Steel Wire-drawers Trade and Sick Benefit Society, Publication (Reel 30)
  - Item 6: Rules of the Friendly Society of Ironfounders, Publication (Reel 30)
  - Item 7: Rural World - Birmingham, Publication (Reel 30)
- Items 289-298, 1884-1900; Microfilm (Reel 31)
  - Item 1: The Rights of Labor, arranged by Thomas Barclay, Publication (Reel 31)
    By Ruskin, John. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Song of the Respectables and other verse, Publication (Reel 31)
    By Salt, Henry. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Socialism, Labor, and Capital, Publication (Reel 31)
    By Samuelson, J. (Ed.), J. Holyoake, Rev. M. Kaufman, and S. Stepniak. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Methods of Industrial Remuneration (3rd Ed.), Publication (Reel 31)
    By Schloss, David F. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: A Course of Lectures, Publication (Reel 31)
    By Sheffield Labor Association. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Should the Working Class Support the Liberal Party?, Publication (Reel 31)
    By Harry Quelch; Gorrie Grang. A debate between Mr Harry Quelch and Mr. Gorrie Grant (Lib. M.P.). Item is in English.
  - Item 7: The Christian, the Atheist, and the Socialist, Publication (Reel 31)
    By Shufflebotham, J. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Women and Work, Publication (Reel 31)
    By Simon, Jules. 1 Sept. 1891. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: The Crimes of Government, Publication (Reel 31)
    By Sketchley, J. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: A Review of European Society, Publication (Reel 31)
- Items 299-304, 1887-1899; Microfilm (Reel 32)
  - Item 1: The Economics of Temperance, Publication (Reel 32)
    By Smart, H. Russell. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Factory Industry and Socialism, Publication (Reel 32)
    By Smart, William. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Socialism and Drink, Publication (Reel 32)
  - Item 4: The Great Strike and its Lesson, Publication (Reel 32)
    By Smee, Alfred H. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: The New Trades Combination Movement, Publication (Reel 32)
    By Smith, E.J. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Social Democrat - A Monthly Socialist Review Vols. 1 and 2, Publication (Reel 32)
- Items 305-337, 1883-1900; Microfilm (Reel 33)
  - Item 1: Social-Democratic Federation - Grand Bazaar and Fancy Fair, Publication (Reel 33)
    Dec. 26-27 1900. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Socialism! - Lecture by Sidney Webb, Publication (Reel 33)
    Nov. 4, 1890. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Socialism and Trade Unionism, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 4: Socialism Made Plain, Publication (Reel 33)
    1883 and 1886. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Socialist League - Open Air Meetings, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 6: Socialist League - Chants for Socialists, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 7: Socialist League - Socialist Leaflets No. 2 'Down with Socialists!', Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 8: Socialist League Meetings - Leicester 1889, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 9: Socialist League Meetings - Leicester 1889, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 10: Socialist League - Manifesto on the Sudan War, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 11: Socialist League - Leaflet No. 1 'Why be Transported?', Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 12: Songs for Socialists, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 13: Socialism and the Worker, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Sorge, F.A. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Socialism and the Worker, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 15: Education and its Meaning, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Stacy, Enid. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: Is Socialism Desireable? - A Debate, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Stacey, Enid and Rev. A. Seton. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: John Bull and Doctor Socialism, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Suthers, R.B. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: Wine and Milk, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Tamlyn, John. Item is in English.
  - Item 19: Tailoring Trade Dispute Inquiry, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 20: On-Profit Sharing Between Capital and Labor, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Taylor, Sedley. Item is in English.
  - Item 21: A Prospectus of Socialism, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Thomson, William. Item is in English.
  - Item 22: Hail Referendum!, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Thompson, A.M. Item is in English.
  - Item 23: The Only Way to Democracy, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 24: The Referendum and Initiative in Practice, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 25: That Blessed Word - Liberty, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 26: The Rise of the English Democracy, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Thompson, William M. Item is in English.
  - Item 27: The Gas Strike, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Thorne, W. and M. Hutchins. Item is in English.
  - Item 28: The New Departure in Trades Unionism, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Threlfall, T.R. Item is in English.
  - Item 29: An Address on Character and Environment, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Tillett, Ben. Item is in English.
  - Item 30: Trades Unionism and Socialism, Publication (Reel 33)
  - Item 31: The Redemption of Labor, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Tillett, Caleb. Item is in English.
  - Item 32: The State Carriage, Publication (Reel 33)
    By Timewell, J. Item is in English.
  - Item 33: To Trades Unionists: Open-Air Meetings, Publication (Reel 33)
- Item 338, 1884; Microfilm (Reel 34)
  - Item 1: To-Day: The Monthly Magazine of Scientific Socialism Vol. 1 and 2, Publication (Reel 34)
- Items 339-345, 1890-1898; Microfilm (Reel 35)
  - Item 1: Torch: A Journal of Anarchist-Communism, Publication (Reel 35)
    August 1894-September 1895. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Progress and Poverty, Publication (Reel 35)
    By Toynbee, Arnold. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Trade Unionist, Publication (Reel 35)
    April-August 1891. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Travelling Card and Instructions, Publication (Reel 35)
  - Item 5: The Neglect of the Poor in Workhouse Infirmaries, Publication (Reel 35)
    By Twinning, Louisa. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: United Society of Boiler Makers and Iron Shipbuilders - Contribution Card, Publication (Reel 35)
  - Item 7: Fair Play: Poverty and its Causes, Publication (Reel 35)
    By Varon. Item is in English.
- Items 346-351, 1883-1900; Microfilm (Reel 36)
  - Item 1: Social Peace, Publication (Reel 36)
    By Von-Schulze-Gavernitz, Dr. G. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Wage-Earning Childern - Report of Committee, Publication (Reel 36)
  - Item 3: The "Why" and "How" of Land Nationalization, Publication (Reel 36)
    By Wallace, A.R. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Wanted: Order!, Publication (Reel 36)
  - Item 5: War Against War: A Chrinicle of the International Crusade of Peace, Publication (Reel 36)
    January-March 1899. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: The Co-operative Movement in Great Britain, Publication (Reel 36)
    By Webb, Beatrice. Item is in English.
- Items 352-359, 1888-1897; Microfilm (Reel 37)
  - Item 1: The Dock Life of East London, Publication (Reel 37)
    By Webb, Beatrice. October 1887. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: East London Labor, Publication (Reel 37)
    By Webb, Beatrice. August 1888. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Pages from a Work-Girl's Diary, Publication (Reel 37)
    By Webb, Beatrice. September 1888. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Labor in the Longest Reign, Publication (Reel 37)
    By Webb, Sidney. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: The London Programme, Publication (Reel 37)
  - Item 6: Socialism in England, Publication (Reel 37)
  - Item 7: What Socialism Means, Publication (Reel 37)
  - Item 8: Industrial Democracy, Publication (Reel 37)
    By Webb, Sidney and Beatrice. Item is in English.
- Items 360-373, 1892-1898; Microfilm (Reel 38)
  - Item 1: Problems of Modern Industry, Publication (Reel 38)
  - Item 2: Socialism, Publication (Reel 38)
    By Westcott, Rev. Brooke Foss. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: What is Anarchism?, Publication (Reel 38)
  - Item 3: What is Anarchism?, Publication (Reel 38)
  - Item 5: The Casul Ward System: Its Horrors and Atrocities, Publication (Reel 38)
    By Widdup, J.R. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: The Meaning of Socialism, Publication (Reel 38)
  - Item 7: What Political Economy Teaches, Publication (Reel 38)
  - Item 8: The Sword and the Everlasting Image, Publication (Reel 38)
    By Williams, Antonia. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: The Early History of the Social-Democratic Federations, Publication (Reel 38)
    By Williams, John E. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: With the "Red Vans", Publication (Reel 38)
  - Item 11: Women's Suffrage, Publication (Reel 38)
  - Item 12: The Works and the War, Publication (Reel 38)
  - Item 13: The Workman Times, Publication (Reel 38)
    August 1890. Item is in English.
- Item 373, 1880-1900; Microfilm (Reel 39)
  - Item 1: The Workman Times, Publication (Reel 39)
- Item 374, 1890; Microfilm (Reel 40)
  - Item 1: The Yorkshire Factory Times, Publication (Reel 40)
    Periodical. Item is in English.
- Items 355-376, 1885-1888; Microfilm (Reel 41)
  - Item 1: The Anti-Sweater, Publication (Reel 41)
    By Lyons, Lewis (Editor). July 1886 - Feb. 1887. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Clarion, Publication (Reel 41)
    By Nunquam. Item is in English.
- Item 377, 1886-1891; Microfilm (Reel 42)
  - Item 1: Commonwealth: The Official Journal of the Socialist League, Publication (Reel 42)
    By Morris, William (editor). Item is in English.
- Item 378-379, 1886-1891; Microfilm (Reel 43)
  - Item 1: English Laborer's Chronicle, Publication (Reel 43)
    April-December 1877. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Freedom: A Journal of Anarchist-Socialism, Publication (Reel 43)
    Oct. 1886 - Dec. 1891. Item is in English.
- Item 379, 1892-1900; Microfilm (Reel 44)
  - Item 1: Freedom (continued), Publication (Reel 44)
    Jan. 1892- Dec. 1900. Item is in English.
- Items 379-380, 1890-1905; Microfilm (Reel 45)
  - Item 1: Freedom (continued), Publication (Reel 45)
    Jan. 1901 - Dec. 1905. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Free Russia: The Organ of the English Society of Friends of Russain Freedom, Publication (Reel 45)
    June 1890-Dec. 1897. Item is in English.
- Items 380-381, 1896-1899; Microfilm (Reel 46)
  - Item 1: Free Russia (continued), Publication (Reel 46)
    Jan. 1898 - Dec. 1899. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Song of the Respectables and other Verse, Publication (Reel 46)